royalacademy.org.uk 2017-02-01

# Privacy policy | Royal Academy of Arts

  * ## What this policy covers

The Royal Academy of Arts is committed to protecting your personal information, whether you are a visitor, ticket-buyer, Friend, shopper or other supporter. This policy explains how the RA, and its associated group companies (listed below), collect, manage and use the personal information you provide to us, whether online, via phone, email, in writing or any other correspondence. In some of the other ways we interact with you, additional terms and conditions may also apply that set out additional ways we may use your personal information. We ensure that we may use your personal information in accordance with all applicable laws concerning data protection and personal information. This policy explains: 

    * The information the RA collects about you and why we collect it 
    * How we will store and manage that data
    * What we do with the data we collect and store and how we use it  

    * Your choices regarding the information you provide to us

  * ## Who we are

The Royal Academy of Arts exists to promote art and artists – a mission we pursue through exhibitions, education and debate. The Friends of the RA, the RA Shop, Art Sales and other commercial endeavours support the Academy in this mission.  
The RA is a registered UK charity (with charity number 1125383). We are also a registered company limited by guarantee in England and Wales with registration number 06298947.  
R. A. Enterprises Ltd (Company number 01666333), The Friends of the Royal Academy (Charity number 272926, company number 01291535), The Royal Academy Trust (Charity number 1067270) and RA (Arts) Limited (Company number 02836364) are all either wholly owned subsidiaries of the RA which trade on its behalf or charities whose objects are to support the RA. Within the context of this policy “we” and the term “across the RA” means both the RA and its associate group of companies. 

  * ## What we collect

We may collect personal information about you when you engage with us for a number of reasons including when you: book a ticket; become a member; enquire about our activities and services; engage with our social media; make a donation; sign up to receive emails; create an online account; purchase something from us; register for an event or otherwise provide us with personal information that may be used to enhance your experience or enable us to provide a service to you.  
We may also receive information about you from third parties. This can include information such as your name, postal address, email address, phone number, credit/debit card details and whether you are a tax payer so that we can claim Gift Aid.  
We may also gather information about the use of our websites, such as which pages are most visited and which events or facilities are of most interest. We will use this information to improve our website and to ensure we provide the best services for users. Wherever possible we use aggregated or anonymous information which does not identify individual visitors to our websites. By submitting your details you enable us (and where applicable any suppliers we use) to provide you with the activities, goods, services, events or online content you select and any other related services the RA may provide.  
We do not usually collect ‘sensitive personal data’ from you unless there is a clear reason for doing so, such as where we need this information to ensure that we provide appropriate support, to enable you to enjoy everything we offer across the RA. 

  * ## Website users

The RA website uses cookies to help our website work well and to track information about how people are using it. More information on cookies and how to control the cookies we use can be found on the cookies page on our website.  
If you register on our website then the following will also apply: 

    * The RA website will collect personal information when you register with us  

    * The website will collect information such as your name, email address and post code. Once you register with the website you will not be anonymous to us when you subsequently sign in  

    * As part of the registration process and continued use of RA services, you agree to endeavour to ensure that any registration information you give to the RA will always be accurate, correct and up to date  

    * We collect and retain information about your transactions with us so that we can process your transactions and deal with future queries  

    * Through your use of cookies, we will receive information from your computer such as your IP address (the unique number that identifies your computer when you use the internet) and we may record this information to provide you with a good experience when browsing our website or to improve the functionality of our site.

  * ## Your debit card and credit card information

If you use your credit or debit card to donate to us, buy something or pay for a registration online or over the phone, we will ensure that this is done securely and in accordance with the Payment Industry Data Security Standard.

  * ## Job applicants

If you apply to work at the RA, we will only use the information you give us to process your application and to monitor recruitment statistics. If we want to disclose information to someone outside the RA, for example, if we need a reference, we will make sure we tell you beforehand, unless we are required to disclose this information by law. 

If you are unsuccessful in your job application, we may hold your personal information for up to 12 months after we’ve finished recruiting for the post you applied for. After this date we will destroy or delete your information. We keep de-personalised statistical information about applicants to develop our recruitment processes, however no individual applicant would be identifiable from this information. If you commence employment with the RA, your data will be processed in accordance with your employment contract and other applicable policies.

  * ## How we may use your information

We may use your information for a number of purposes including the following: 

    * To provide you with the services, products or information you have requested or which we feel may interest you where you have consented to being contacted  

    * To process donations we may receive from you  

    * To create an account for you if you register with us  

    * To provide you with information about our work or our activities that you have agreed to receive  

    * To fulfil sales contracts you have entered into with us  

    * For customer service or administrative purposes (for example we may contact you regarding a donation you have made or an event you have registered or booked a ticket for)  

    * For internal record keeping, including the management of any feedback or complaints  

    * To target communications and messages to you and to identify similar groups  

    * To invite you to participate in surveys or research (although this is voluntary)  

    * To use IP addresses to identify your approximate location, to block disruptive use, to record website traffic or to personalise the way our information is presented to you  

    * To analyse and improve the services offered on our site and to make it as user-friendly as possible  

    * Where it is required or authorised by law  

    * We may assess your personal information for the purposes of credit risk reduction or fraud prevention.  

If you enter your contact details into one of our online forms, we may use this information to contact you, even if you don’t click ‘submit’ on the form. We will only do this to see if we can help with any problems you might be experiencing with the form or with our website.

  * ## Marketing purposes

We may contact you for marketing purposes by email or text message if you have agreed to be contacted in this manner for marketing purposes and do not opt out of receiving further marketing information. We may also send you service communications via email or text, for example where you placed an order for goods or services on our website, or you have given a donation by text.  
If you have provided us with your postal address or telephone number we may send you direct mail or telephone you about our work, unless you have told us that you would prefer not to receive such information.  
It is your choice as to whether you want to receive information about our work and the ways you can get involved. You may opt out of marketing emails at any time by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link in our marketing emails, and can opt out of receiving marketing texts by sending us an ‘opt out’ text message. You can also change any of your marketing preferences at any time (including telling us that you don’t want us to contact you for marketing purposes by telephone or send you direct marketing by post) by contacting our Customer Services team on 020 7300 8090 or [tickets@royalacademy.org.uk](mailto:tickets@royalacademy.org.uk). We will not use your information for marketing purposes if you have indicated that you do not wish to be contacted for such purposes. However, we will retain your details on a suppression list to help ensure that we do not continue to contact you.

  * ## Information sharing and disclosure

The RA may share your personal information with the other RA entities, trading subsidiaries, suppliers or service providers to provide the products or services you’ve requested from us, for example, we may use a separate company to deliver goods to you.  
We may disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to disclose your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies), or in order to enforce or apply our rights (including in relation to our website or other applicable terms and conditions) or to protect the RA, for example in cases of suspected fraud or defamation.

  * ## Under 18s

We are committed to protecting the privacy of the young people who engage with us through our website, our events and at schools. When we collect data about a child or young person aged under 18, we will make it very clear as to the reasons for collecting this data and how it will be used. 

  * ## Inappropriate website content

If you post or send any content that we believe to be inappropriate, offensive or in breach of any laws, such as defamatory content, we may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as your internet provider or law enforcement agencies.

  * ## Where we may store your information

For financial and technical reasons we may, on occasion need to use the services of a supplier outside the European Economic Area (EEA), however we will ensure that your information is held in compliance with the European data protection regulations. By submitting your personal information you agree to this transfer, storing or processing at a location outside the EEA. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is kept secure and in accordance with this privacy policy.

  * ## Keeping your records

We keep records for as long as required to operate the service in accordance with legal requirements and tax and accounting rules. Where your information is no longer required, we will ensure it is disposed of in a secure manner.

  * ## Your ability to edit and delete your account information and preferences

The accuracy of your information is important to us. You can edit your RA account information, including your address and contact details at any time. If you would like to change your preferences or update the details we hold about you other than online, please contact our Customer Services on 020 7300 8090 or [comment@royalacademy.org.uk](mailto:comment@royalacademy.org.uk).  
Under the Data Protection Act 1998 you have a right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. We require you to prove your identity with two pieces of approved identification. Please address requests to the Legal Counsel, The Royal Academy of Arts, Piccadilly, London, W1J 0BD and we will respond to you within 40 days. Please provide as much information as possible about the nature of your contact with us to help us locate your records. We reserve the right to charge a fee of £10 for this process.

  * ## Links

This policy applies to all data we collect across the RA, including our websites. So if a link on this website takes to you to the website of a third party you should refer to the privacy policy relating to that website to understand how your personal information is managed by that third party or how they use cookies. We cannot accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

  * ## Changes to this privacy policy

We may update the terms of this policy at any time, so please do check it from time to time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address you have provided to us or by placing a prominent notice on our website. By continuing to engage with us through our services and our website you will be deemed to have accepted such changes. 

**September 2015**
